# **Endia Williams**

Full-Stack Software Engineer

### **Portfolio**

endia.dev

Contact

github.com/endiawilliams 🖸

contact@endia.dev

linkedin.com/in/endia-dev in

631-948-4568

Kansas City, MO 64133  $\mathbf{Q}$ 

## Summary

I am a full-stack software engineer who loves a challenge. After teaching myself HTML at the age of 12, my curiosity only continued to grow. Many years later I am now a Linux user and I solve new technical challenges every day. I am excited to learn any new technologies that come my way while continuing to deliver clean and elegant code.

### Skills

HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Python, React & React Native, Node, Express, Next.js, Expo, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud, CI/CD, Git & GitHub

## **Projects**

### **Minesweeper: Birthday Edition**

Created a birthday-themed Minesweeper clone in HTML, CSS & JavaScript which utilizes DOM manipulation to correctly identify which element the user has clicked on. Utilized recursion to check all adjacent squares and their values to determine which ones to reveal.

### **BetterCupid** + CI/CD

- Created a full-stack React app with full CRUD functionality & authentication using Bcrypt & Passport. Features Node & Express on the backend. Users can like each other, & every mutual like shows up on the Matches page.
- Implemented automated testing with Jest & Enzyme, continuous integration with GitHub Actions & continuous deployment to Google Cloud Kubernetes Engine.
- Plans for further development include a block feature and instant messaging using Twilio API.

#### **Virtual Glovebox**

Created a cross-platform mobile app using React Native, Tailwind CSS, Next.js, Expo & Firebase for the 2021 DeveloperWeek Hackathon. Users can keep all of their carrelated paperwork conveniently in one place.

### **Education**

#### **Software Engineering Immersive**

General Assembly (2020)

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

#### Liberal Arts

Ivy Tech Community College, Indianapolis, IN (2013-2014)

### **Experience**

#### **Client Coordinator**

FrontStreet Facility Solutions, Ronkonkoma, NY (2018–2019)

Assisted 12 retail clients as needed to secure handymen for repair service, while meeting SLA requirements for response time & maintaining or exceeding a 20% profit margin.

#### Shift Lead

Speedway Convenience Store, Wading River, NY (2017-2018)